<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben&#39;s Thoughts</title>
    <link>http://soukia.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ben&#39;s Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://soukia.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity Traps</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/sans-titre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/sans-titre/</guid>
      <description>What makes us fall into the complexity trap?  Perfection is achieved, not when there is nothing more to add, but when there is nothing left to take away. Antoine de Saint-Exupery
 I love this quote because it describes simplicity not on the basis of what is here but on the basis of what is not. Simplicity is not about having as little as possible as a goal in and of itself, but rather of minimizing what is not essential so that greater focus can be achieved on what really is important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback Delays</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/feedback-delays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/feedback-delays/</guid>
      <description>Feedback delays : the surprising link between faucet design and Machine Learning. Thinking in Systems by Donella Meadows is a great introduction to the discipline of system modeling and analysis. One of the chapters of the book explains how feedback delays in a system with balancing loops can cause systems to oscillate before stabilizing closer to their desired state.
I know this might sound like gibberish if you are foreign to system modeling, but this is actually a simple and powerful idea with many real-world application, one of which you’ve probably experienced yourself more than once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/photography/</guid>
      <description> Photography San Sebastian Norway Paris Lisbonne Iceland Nepal India </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forces of Progress</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/forces-of-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/forces-of-progress/</guid>
      <description>The Forces of Progress I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about the jobs to be done methodology lately. It’s a useful framework to get to the roots of customer needs.
The theory makes the points that to innovate, companies must take a step back from the first degree needs of their customers to understand the more fundamental progress they are trying to achieve. To do so, they must understand the « job » people hire their product to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The third pillar</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/third-pillar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/third-pillar/</guid>
      <description>The third pillar of online education Why hasn’t internet replaced universities yet ? A few years ago, when platforms such as Coursera and Udacity popped up, the bullish vision for online education saw an inevitable long-term demise of the university system.
With online education, you would access world class education for free or for a fraction of what is usually cost. Having an open access to educational content would put everyone at the same playing-level field, decreasing information asymmetry and increasing competition between students.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>