<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ben&#39;s Thoughts</title>
    <link>http://soukia.be/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ben&#39;s Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://soukia.be/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Risk, Market Risk</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/product-risk-market-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/product-risk-market-risk/</guid>
      <description>Product Risk, Market Risk One of the big and unavoidable question when building a new product is knowing when to launch. Should you get an MVP out as fast as possible, get feedback and iteratively adjust your product features and strategy or should you wait for a near-perfect V1 that delights its first customers?
The dominant school of thought of the last years has been the lean startup movement, which advocates clearly and equivocally for the former.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Inefficiencies</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/communication-inefficiencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/communication-inefficiencies/</guid>
      <description>Communication inefficiencies : Is there room for yet another communication tool ? Most organizations, once they grow above a certain size, struggle to maintain good communication flows among different teams. Yet, except if you’re Apple or Palantir, there is a good chance that transparency and a relatively free and efficient information distribution among co-workers can help create a more aligned and productive workplace, and as such is highly valuable to business outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity traps</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/complexity-traps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/complexity-traps/</guid>
      <description>What makes us fall into the complexity trap?  Perfection is achieved, not when there is nothing more to add, but when there is nothing left to take away. Antoine de Saint-Exupery
 I love this quote because it describes simplicity not on the basis of what is here but on the basis of what is not. Simplicity is not about having as little as possible as a goal in and of itself, but rather of minimizing what is not essential so that greater focus can be achieved on what really is important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback delays</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/feedback-delays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/feedback-delays/</guid>
      <description>Feedback delays : the surprising link between faucet design and Machine Learning. Thinking in Systems by Donella Meadows is a great introduction to the discipline of system modeling and analysis. One of the chapters of the book explains how feedback delays in a system with balancing loops can cause systems to oscillate before stabilizing closer to their desired state.
I know this might sound like gibberish if you are foreign to system modeling, but this is actually a simple and powerful idea with many real-world application, one of which you’ve probably experienced yourself more than once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forces of Progress</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/forces-of-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/forces-of-progress/</guid>
      <description>The Forces of Progress I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about the jobs to be done methodology lately. It’s a useful framework to get to the roots of customer needs.
The theory makes the points that to innovate, companies must take a step back from the first degree needs of their customers to understand the more fundamental progress they are trying to achieve. To do so, they must understand the « job » people hire their product to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Timing</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/feature-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/feature-timing/</guid>
      <description>Feature Timing One of the well known pitfalls when building a product is the bias toward adding features as a way to improve the overall product experience and build engagement. Much has been written about why this approach rarely works and an opposing, more purist school of thought take pride in building products with minimalists feature sets.
When determining if one should build a feature, the discussion often fall around the tension between some sort of static set of beliefs: the minimalist designer who wants to keep things simple vs the “built it and they will come” engineer who wants to add new features to please a vocal but marginal set of users (and possibly increase complexity).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convenience &amp; high fidelity</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/convenience-fidelity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/convenience-fidelity/</guid>
      <description>Convenience &amp;amp; high fidelity I read a book a while back called Trade-offs. The central premise was that the way people experience products or services can be mapped on a chart called the fidelity swap which showcases Fidelity on the Y axis and Convenience on the X axis.
In the context of this chart, fidelity refers to the total experience of something whereas convenience refers to how easy or hard is it to get what you want (It encompass availability, price, ease of use).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perception of Design</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/perception-of-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/perception-of-design/</guid>
      <description>The Perception of Design (2016) When I started designing website mockups for my first company, Showmade, I had no significant design experience. Looking back on those and the early versions of the website, I realize they really sucked.
But back when I made those, I thought they were good. Maybe this was just another instance of the Dunning-Kruger effect. Most likely my perception and understanding of good design was too narrow to appreciate what was bad about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/photography/</guid>
      <description> Photography San Sebastian Norway Paris Lisbonne Budapest Iceland Nepal India </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The third pillar</title>
      <link>http://soukia.be/posts/third-pillar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://soukia.be/posts/third-pillar/</guid>
      <description>The third pillar of online education Why hasn’t internet replaced universities yet ? A few years ago, when platforms such as Coursera and Udacity popped up, the bullish vision for online education saw an inevitable long-term demise of the university system.
With online education, you would access world class education for free or for a fraction of what is usually cost. Having an open access to educational content would put everyone at the same playing-level field, decreasing information asymmetry and increasing competition between students.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>